Okay, good afternoon, good evening or good night, good morning,
好的，下午好，傍晚好，晚上好，早上好，
whatever timezone you're in watching this lecture.
无论你在哪个时区收看这个课程。
Double checking on sound, people can hear me?
再次检查声音，大家能听到我说话吗？
Yes yes.
是的。
Sure, okay, I'm gonna talk about two things today,
好的，今天我要谈两件事，
I want to finish off our discussion to FaRM
我想结束我们对 FaRM 的讨论，
and then I'll talk about spark.
然后我会讨论 Spark 。
And just to remind everybody else,
只想提醒大家，
so everybody we were more FaRM,
所以每个人，我们（讨论）更多 FaRM ，
we're talked about executing transaction and without any failures
我们讨论了执行事务，没有任何失败，
and we looked at one example
我们看了一个例子，
of whether actually the transaction provided external consistency or strict serializability.
事务是否提供了外部一致性或严格的可串行化。
And, so I want to talk about one more example,
所以，我想再谈一个例子，
to look about to talk about serializability,
来讨论可串行化，
and then talk a little bit about fault tolerance,
然后讨论一下容错，
but before doing so,
但在此之前，
it's probably helpful to remind,
提醒一下可能会有帮助，
my remind ourselves exactly,
提醒我们事务是如何工作的，
if there are no failures,
如果没有故障。
and so in FaRM and application goes for two phases,
在 FaRM 中，应用程序分为两个阶段，
the execution phase, where it fetches objects you know from different shards
执行阶段，从不同的分片获取对象，
and then the commit phase.
然后是提交阶段。
And so we look back at this picture here,
所以我们回到这张图片，
you know there's an execution phase three objects being, three objects being read,
有一个执行阶段，
you know one from each different shard,
每个来自不同的分片，
you know we have shard one, shard two and shard three,
我们有分片一，分片二，分片三，
and every shard has one backup,
每个分片都有一个备份，
so this system could tolerate one failure.
所以，这个系统可以容忍一个故障。
So object to read the the two objects are being modified,
所以一个对象读取，两个对象正在被修改，
as we see in the second
正如我们稍后会看到的，
and then once you know the three objects read and two modified,
一旦三个对象被读取，两个对象被修改，
the application might decide to commit
应用程序可能决定提交，
and then so the whole commit phase goes into action,
然后，整个提交阶段就开始了，
this whole story from steps one through five,
整个故事从第一步到第五步，
and in step one, the transaction takes out of locks
在第一步中，事务获取锁，
on the objects that have been written written,
在写入的对象上，
so we see here there have been two objects that have been written to by the transaction
我们在这里可以看到，
and so we're propagating what's called locked records you know to every primary.
所以，我们传播锁记录给每个 primary ，
So every primary is going to have a lock record for this transaction,
所以，每个 primary 都将拥有这个事务的锁记录，
and for the objects involved in the transaction,
对于事务中涉及的对象，
so and lockg records contains an object id,
锁记录包含一个对象 id ，
which identifies the object uniquely a version number,
唯一地标识对象，
so at the time that transaction reads an object,
在事务读取对象时，
it gets back a version number,
它会得到一个版本号，
in fact gets back this 64 bit number,
得到这个 64 位数字，
which is top is a log bit and the rest is version number,
其顶部是锁位，其余是版本号，
and then a new value.
然后是一个新的值。
So, you know primary one and primary two is going to have,
所以， primary 1 和 primary 2 会有，
primary one is going to have to lock record for object one,
primary 会有对象 1 的锁记录，
primary two is going to have to lock object for primary for object two,
primary 2 会有对象 2 的锁记录，
then there's a separate phase for the validation of the read-only operations or operations,
然后有一个单独的阶段用于验证只读操作，
as we can see in those validation step,
正如我们在这些验证步骤中所看到的，
the dotted lines represent one-sided RDMAs.
虚线表示单边 RDMA ，
And as we talked about on Tuesday,
正如我们周二谈到的，
those basically involve no server involvement,
它们不涉及服务器，
you know sender can just read a an object out of the memory of the server,
发送者能从服务器的内存中读取一个对象，
which actually have without actually having to interrupt the computation, that's actually running on the server.
不需要，
So they tend to be very fast,
所以它们往往非常快，
unlike you know these operations that we saw here,
不像我们在这里看到的这些操作，
which are actually write RDMAs.
它们是写入 RDMA ，
They are cool too,
它们也很酷，
in the sense that you get to write you know to the appends you know to this log record
在某种意义上，你必须写入，
without actually interrupting the server,
不需要中断服务器，
but the server actually has to process these log records
但服务器必须处理这些日志记录，
and and the server in this case,
本例中的服务器，
once it actually process one of these log records,
一旦它处理了这些日志记录之一，
you know tries to take out the lock,
试图获取锁，
if it succeeds trying to take the lock,
如果它成功地获取锁，
because the version number hasn't changed
因为版本号没有改变，
or to the lock bit or no other transactions taking the lock,
或锁位或没有其他事务获取该锁，
then it will reply back,
然后它会回复，
you know using another one of write RDMA saying okay.
用另一个写入 RDMA 说 ok 。
And so yeah we see that on the acquiring lock,
所以，我们在获取锁上看到，
requires action on the server,
需要在服务器上执行操作，
but the one-sided RDMA for reads validation,
但用于读取验证的单边 RDMA ，
doesn't require any action on the server.
不需要在服务器上执行任何操作。
Then, there's there,
然后，就是这样，
if everything turns out to be okay,
如果一切顺利，
so, transactions basically able to obtain those write locks
事务能够获得这些写入锁，
and validate you know the read operations,
并验证读取操作，
it actually makes a decision to commit
它会做出提交的决定，
and to commit it a first communicates to every backup, the object the change,
为了提交，它首先联系每个备份，
so write to commit backup record.
写入提交备份记录，
It depends that to every, to the backups of the objects that have been modified,
这取决于每个，对于已修改的对象的备份，
again you know it's basically a copy of the log record,
同样，它是锁记录的复制，
you know oid goes in there the version number goes in there and the new value.
oid 在那里，版本号在那里，新值在那里。
Once you know all the backups you know have have reported,
一旦所有备份都回复，
that they actually have a copy of the object,
它们有对象的复制，
now we're basically in pretty good shape,
现在我们处于很好的状态，
because the primary has copy, the backup has to copy,
因为 primary 有复制，备份有复制，
[] the primary doesn't really know if the transaction has been committed yet or not,
[]primary 并不知道，
and so the final step is not actually the coordinator or detection coordinator write out and commit a record,
所以，最后一步是，
and commit primary record,
并提交主记录，
informing the primaries that actually do transaction actually has committed.
通知 primary 事务已经提交。
And as soon as it gets an acknowledgement from one of the NICs,
一旦收到其中一个网卡的确认，
you know indicated by the dotted lines,
由虚线表示的，
it actually reports back to the application,
它向应用程序报告，
saying that the transaction committed.
说这个事务已经提交。
So what we wanna do now is look at two cases,
所以我们现在要做的是看两个案例，
one we wanted to talk a little bit more about serializability,
一个我们想更多地讨论一下可串行化，
just to see if the concurrency control work out
为了看看并发控制是否起作用，
and then we'll talk a little bit about fault tolerance
然后我们会稍微谈一下容错，
and see if the fault tolerance story works out.
看看容错是否起作用。
Aha, so let me first start with serializability,
让我首先从可串行化开始，
alright, so maybe before doing that,
也许在这么做之前，
let me just ask if any questions so far,
我想问问，目前有没有什么问题，
or whether everybody should have swapped, successfully swapped FaRM back into into your memories.
或者是否每个人都切换，
What does the rectangle mean in this?
长方形在这里是什么意思？
Picture?
抱歉?
So what's the rectangle,
长方形是什么，
what does it signify along.
这意味着什么？
The object.
它是对象。
Oh, it's an object, okay.
哦，这是对象，好的。
Okay, any other questions?
好的，还有其他问题吗？
Okay, good, let's, so let's let's look at the correctness from the concurrency perspective,
好的，让我们，
so the correct correctness strict serializability.
所以严格串行化的正确性。
And on Tuesday, we looked at transaction that didn't really evolve write validation,
在周二，我们研究了
because there was no object was read, but not written,
因为对象被读取，而不是写入，
and so I'm going to look at another transaction this time around,
所以这一次我要看看另一个事务，
where actually the validation phase and plays a role.
在那里验证阶段发挥了作用。
And so we look at two transactions,
所以我们来看两个事务，
and this is sort of this example,
这是，
of course, it's not going to be approved,
当然，它不会被证明，
but if you're one of these key examples,
但它是关键的例子之一，
but generally it's very helpful to see, to understand how the protocol works,
总的来说，对了解协议是如何工作的非常有帮助。
the protocol, the transactions are if x is 0,
协议，事务是，
so if object x 0, we'll see object y 1,
如果对象 x 是 0 ，我们设置对象 y 1 ，
which is transaction 2 sort of the opposite,
事务 2 正好相反，它是，
And the reason of this sort of,
之所以这样，
this is a good test for serializability,
这是一个很好的可串行化测试，
is that either transaction 1 should go after T2, correct,
无论事务 1 应该在 T2 之后进行，
or T2 should go after T1
或者 T2 应该在 T1 之后
and depending on which order you run,
根据您运行的顺序，
you know either y is 1, or x is 1,
要么 y 是 1 ，要么 x 是 1 ，
but you never should have, you never should have the outcome said x is 1, oops, the x is 1, and y is 1.
但你永远不会有，
And that should not be a lot,
这是不允许的，
because definitely violates serializability.
因为这肯定违反了可串行化。
Does that make sense?
这能理解吗？
Okay, so what do we want to do is to test,
好的，我们要做的是，
in a, we want to understand requirements,
我们想要了解需求，
and indeed a it is not possible that x is 1 and y is 1 get produced.
实际上， x 是 1 ， y 是 1 是不可能产生的。
So let's look at the timeline,
那么让我们来看看时间线，
let's say we're we have T1, here we have T2 timeline.
假设这里有 T1 ，这里有 T2 时间线，
So they both you know in their sort of the preparation or execution phase,
它们都处于准备或执行阶段，
both reads these objects,
都读取这些对象，
so let's say they run through the concurrently,
所以我们假设它们同时运行，
we do a read of x and version number 0,
我们读取 x 和版本号 0 ，
we do a read of y, the version number 0,
我们读取 y ，版本号为 0 ，
same here.
这里也一样。
And of course T1 will update y, T2 will update x
当然 T1 会更新 y ， T2 会更新 x ，
and the base at some point you know those start to commit phase.
它们在某个点上，开始提交阶段，
And you know let's,
让我们，
so let's say the T1 that starts first
让我们假设 T1 先开始，
and basically grabs the, it needs to lock on y,
它需要对 y 加锁，
since it's going to be writing y,
因为它将写入 y ，
so, let's say x successfully grab the lock and y
我们假设 x 成功地获取了 y 的锁，
and so that actually will set the log bit you in the version number of the y object.
所以它会设置对象 y 的锁位和版本号。
And then let's say you know actually,
然后我们假设，
since it's going to read,
因为它要读取，
it has read x,
它读取了 x ，
but it's not as read x,
但它不像读取 x ，
but it's not modifying x, but the validation of x,
但它不是在修改 x ，而是在验证 x ，
you know x was read version number 0,
x 是读取版本号 0 ，
the you know at validation five,
在验证阶段，
so nothing actually has changed with x,
所以 x 并没有改变，
that version number still 0 there,
那里的版本号仍然是 0 ，
you know we're an executed in this order
我们是按这个顺序执行的，
and so things are sort of are fine,
所以一切都很好，
and you know at some point, you know this transaction might commit.
在某个时候，这个事务可能会提交。
So let's look at T2,
那么让我们来看看 T2 ，
let's say you know T2 runs after the validation of x,
假设 T2 在 x 的验证之后运行，
so it grabs the lock,
所以它获取锁，
and and then you know the, it has read y,
它需要读取 y ，
so it needs to do a validation of y.
所以它需要对 y 进行验证，
That's going to do a validation of y
这将对 y 进行验证，
and the question is, is that validation could succeed or not.
问题是，
No, because the previous the other operation has allowed modified value,
不会，因为之前的另一个操作已经获取修改值的锁，
so it's not the same,
所以这与它最初读到的不一样，
Yeah so the version numbers might be still the same,
是的，所以版本号可能还是一样的，
but y, if you T1 [] has set the lock bit, right, for the object y
但是 T1 已经设置了对象 y 的锁位，
and so at this point, this validation will fail,
在这一点上，这个验证将失败，
because it's not the same,
因为这不一样，或者锁位已经设置，
so to T2 transaction, the T2 transaction will abort.
所以，对于 T2 事务， T2 事务将会中止。
Okay, does that makes sense?
好的，这能理解吗？
So we see you at least in this particular example,
所以我们至少在这个特定的例子中看到，
that you know it is the case,
情况就是这样，
that T1 and T2 both don't commit,
T1 和 T2 都提交，
which would result in this incorrect outcome.
将导致这个不正确的结果。
Any questions about this?
对此有什么问题吗？
I I had a question.
我有个问题。
Yeah.
嗯。
Yeah, so, like for for the transactions,
是的，所以，对于事务来说，
so these are like these have to be like update transaction,
所以这些必须有更新事务，
like rewrite correct read,
比如重新写入，
Yeah, go ahead.
好的，继续。
I I just wonder if they were like read operations, you could do that, like log free, right,
我只是在想，
and as long as the.
而且只要。
Yeah, so this is actually, let's go back to this picture here, right,
是的，所以这是，
then let's look at the, let's say, there were no writes involved in this transaction at all, right,
让我们来看一下，
so for example the two obvious have been read correct
比如，两个对象读取，
or store at you know P1 and P2.
保存在 P1 和 P2 。
So let's assume that these guys are actually not involved,
所以我们假设这些并没有参与，
so those objects were not written,
所以这些对象没有写入，
so the only operation that's happening is read with that object.
所以，发生的唯一操作是对这个对象进行读取。
And you see in and so the protocols carefully designed,
你可以看到，协议是精心设计的，
so that if you only do reads,
所以如果你只做读取，
you only do one-sided at RDMAs, correct,
你只做单边 RDMA ，
here in the execution phase
在这里的执行阶段，
and one RDMA to do the validation,
一个 RDMA 来进行验证，
and no locks are taken out,
没有锁被拿出来，
no writes are being done,
没有任何写入，
no records are being appended,
没有附加任何记录，
that's the only thing that happens.
这是唯一发生的事情。
And so this is one of the cool features about FaRM,
所以这是 FaRM 的一个很酷的特点，
is that these transactions that only do reads,
如果事务只做读取，
can be executed without, with only one-sided RDMAs
可以只使用单边 RDMA 执行，
and only with no writes to any locks or grabbing locks
不需要写入任何锁或获取锁，
and so that's why one reason that they get extremely high performance.
这就是它们能获得极高性能的原因之一。
And this is also the reason why,
这也是为什么，
for example the lock phase, the lock step and validation steps are two separate things,
锁步骤和验证步骤是两个不同的事情，
because in for read-only transactions, there's no lock step.
因为在只读事务中，没有锁步骤。
Okay?
好的?
Actually, a question on that,
关于这个问题，
for read-only transactions,
对于只读事务，
why do we need the second valve,
为什么我们需要第二个，
why do we need the validation phase,
为什么我们需要验证阶段，
because aren't you like reading a value,
因为你不是只读取值吗，
and then you're immediately validating right after it, like the version,
然后你在它之后验证版本，
it seems like.
看起来像是。
It could be another transaction,
可能是另一个事务修改对象，
so if transaction ran or started and committed before,
如果事务在之前运行或开始并提交，
okay, the concurrent transaction actual writes might modify the object,
好的，并发事务写入可能会修改对象，
and now, we'll be back right,
现在，我们回来，
so the the the transaction writes,
所以事务写入，
then the transaction that actually follows you know should you know see observed at last write.
然后后面的事务，
But if they occur at the same time,
但如果它们同时发生，
then we can reorder them either way.
然后我们可以以任何一种方式对它们重新排序。
Exactly at the same time, we order reorder them, yeah.
在同一时间，我们可以对它们重新排序，是的。
So it still seems to me, like the second validation,
所以在我看来，
because the first time you read it,
因为你第一次读取它，
the second time you just immediately [] and see the version is the same machine,
第二次直接[]，看到版本是相同的，
it still seems to me like the second validation is like almost unnecessary.
在我看来，第二次验证似乎是不必要的。
I I, you might be right,
你可能是对的，
I haven't thought very hard about this,
我还没好好想过这件事，
that if there, if there are transactions are only read-only transactions,
如果事务只是只读事务，
you know then the validation is definitely not necessary,
那么验证肯定是不必要的，
I have very carefully thought about,
我非常仔细地考虑过，
when there's a mix of transactions,
当有混合事务时，
where there is a case where you need the validation.
你需要验证。
Yeah, what would that be the case,
是的，如果是这样的话，
where like you have like, if you read a value,
如果你读取一个值，
like you expect to read, like two values automatically,
你希望原子地读取两个值，
read value after you read a value,
在读取值之后，
like some transaction modifies the other value.
有事务修改了另一个值。
Yeah, it would be only one possible.
是的，这是一种可能。
When it doesn't.
它不会。
Yeah, sure, I'm not, I'm not quite sure,
是的，我不是很确定，
actually in that case, if that's the problem.
在这种情况下，如果这是问题所在。
Like, for example in this case,
比如在这种情况下，
you know this T1 and T2 cases,
这个 T1 和 T2 的案例，
really crucial that y actually does the validation, correct,
非常关键的一点是 y 做了验证，
even though actually that transaction you know T1 only reads y, right.
即使事务 T1 只读取 y ，
But what if, transaction 2 was just x equals 1,
但是，如果事务 2 只是 x 等于 1 ，
instead of like without that statement.
而没有那个语句。
[Blind write].
盲写。
Hmm?
嗯？
If it is a blind write.
如果这是盲写。
Yeah, it's just x equals one and then it executes after the validation of T1.
是的，它只是 x 等于 1 ，
Yeah that's fine correct.
是的，这是好的。
But whould.
但是。
I'm not sure what the question is.
我不确定问题是什么。
Oh, so if T2 is is just,
哦，所以如果 T2 只是，
like like you know write x equals 1,
比如写入 x 等于 1 ，
within the validation step, after an excuse, after the validation step of T1,
在验证步骤内，
wouldn't then T1 think that x equals 0,
那么 T1 不会认为 x 等于 0 吗，
but then x becomes 1 before the commit.
但是在提交之前， x 变成了 1 。
Okay, so okay, let me maybe we can make a hold up,
好的，也许我们可以先等一下，
because I gotta redraw the whole picture
因为我要重画这张图，
and figure out exactly what the scenario you're talking about.
弄清楚你所说的场景到底是什么。
Okay, so maybe we can go back to this at the end.
好的，也许我们可以在最后回到这个问题上。
Sorry, I had a question,
抱歉，我有个问题，
what is the use case for normal transaction.
正常事务的用例是什么？
If think back Spanner and this paper,
如果回想一下 Spanner 和这个论文，
like there's often the case in these workloads, the TPC-C workload and the TATP workload,
很多情况下，
where you know there's a transaction that only does reads for example,
有一个只读的事务，
I've computed the balances of a set of accounts,
我计算一组账户的余额，
nothing is being written,
什么都没写，
but you know a lot of things, a lot of accounts being read.
但是很多账户被读取。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Okay, so we see here there's actually a validation phase is crucial, correct,
好的，我们在这里看到，验证阶段是至关重要的，
T1 and T2 transaction in in furthermore that actually figures out work out, correct,
T1 和 T2 事务，
we get strict serializability,
我们得到了严格的可串行化，
of course this is not a proof,
当然，这不是证明，
but it gives you you know this example to try to get at the tricky case,
但它给了你这个例子，
you know actually FaRM seems to work out correctly.
FaRM 解决得很好。
Okay so, so that's on the concurrency control,
好的，所以这是关于并发控制的，
then the second part,
然后第二部分，
we want to talk a little bit about is fault tolerance.
我们想讨论一下容错。
And you really want to get the, not gonna go great amount of depth here,
这里不会很深入，
just want to talk about the you know key challenge
只想谈谈关键挑战，
and see you know and build some intuition,
建立一些直觉，
why we might actually be hopeful that FaRM actually addresses the key challenge.
为什么我们希望 FaRM 解决关键挑战。
And so the key challenge,
所以关键的挑战是，
and so we actually have the key challenge is that there's actually crashes after telling the application,
所以我们面临的关键挑战是，
and then it has to be the case, right,
然后它必须是这样，
that the transaction persists.
事务持久化，
Because we have informed the application that the transaction is committed,
因为我们已经通知应用程序事务已提交，
so we can actually lose any writes that the transaction has done.
所以，我们不能丢失事务已完成的所有写入。
And so we can look at this picture again,
所以我们可以再看一下这张图片，
and see if we're, going to be hopeful that this is the case.
看看我们，
So you know there are a couple things you observe,
所以有几个事情需要观察，
after you know the lock phase,
在锁阶段之后，
it is the case that,
情况是这样的，
it's the case that the two primaries P1 and P2 have a lock record,
两个 primary P1 和 P2 具有锁记录，
which describes the update,
描述了更新，
we don't really know the transaction, that record doesn't say whether the record actually,
我们不知道事务，
whether the transaction is committed,
事务是否已经提交，
but we have information about the transaction.
但我们有关于事务的信息，
Then, after this step, to commit backup step,
然后，在这步骤之后，到达提交备份步骤，
we know that you know backup you want B1 and B2 have the commit record.
我们知道备份 B1 和 B2 有提交记录，
And then before you know the transaction,
然后在事务，
the transaction coordinator reports to the application,
事务协调者向应用程序报告之前，
that it has to be successful,
它必须是成功的，
we know that one of the primaries,
我们知道其中一个 primary ，
let's say P1 also has commit record.
假设 P1 也有提交记录，
So you know let's assume there's a crash you know like right here,
我们假设这里发生了崩溃，
so at that particular just after that commit point, you know and the system crashes
所以在那个特定的提交点之后，系统崩溃了，
and what we want to convince ourselves off is that,
我们想要说服自己的是，
if there's one failure,
如果有一次失败，
And so the worst case basically correct is the B2 fails,
所以最坏的情况是， B2 失败了，
so here, where is B2, you know B2 B2 fails.
所以这里 B2 失败了，
And so we lose you know that commit record,
所以我们失去了提交记录，
that is actually there,
它就在那里，
the primary might actually have not a commit record yet.
primary 可能还没有提交记录，
Because you know it crashed after we see if the acknowledgement of one primary,
因为它在我们看到一个 primary 的确认后崩溃了，
so let's say that P1 must actually have to commit record.
所以，我们假设 P1 有提交记录，
So in this case, P1 have to permit record,
在这种情况下， P1 有提交记录，
and you know and of course you know the backup has committed record for B1.
当然备份有 B1 的提交记录，
So this is enough information correct for convince during recovery,
所以，这在恢复时有足够的信息，
that actually the transaction has committed,
事务已经提交，
because you know we have a commit record,
因为我们有提交记录，
which is just what the tid that's committed
这是 tid 提交，
and we actually have all the information at the backups,
我们有备份中的所有信息，
namely the lock, the commit records which describe the write transactions, on the backups
即锁以及描述写事务的提交记录，
and so during recovery, we actually have enough information to decide you know that the transaction actually has committed.
所以，在恢复期间，
And so that's sufficient,
所以这是足够的，
yeah, of course there's a complex protocol,
当然这是一个复杂的协议，
that actually needs to go into action
需要操作，
and sort of look at all the pieces that are left behind by the transaction
看看事务留下的所有部分，
with enough pieces left behind transaction for the coordinator,
有足够多的事务留下的部分，
for the new coordinator the recovery process to decide that actually this transaction indeed has committed and should be persistent.
对于新的协调者，恢复进程来决定，
Okay?
好的?
Good.
好的。
So let me summarize FaRM
所以让我总结一下 FaRM ，
and before we jump into the discussion of spark.
在我们进入关于 Spark 的讨论之前。
So you know top level,
所以高级别的，
you know what's so cool about FaRM is fast,
FaRM 最酷的地方就是快，
it can execute many many, many transactions per second.
它每秒可以执行很多事务，
You know there are some restrictions of course you know on FaRM,
当然 FaRM 有一些限制，
you can't do it all all the time.
你不能一直这样做。
So, first of all,
所以，首先，
it seems few conflicts,
它假设很少有冲突，
so use this optimistic concurrency control scheme
所以使用这个乐观并发控制方案，
and the reason that uses this optimistic concurrency control scheme,
之所以使用这种乐观并发控制方案，
because want to take out locks,
因为想把锁拿出来，
because it wants to do this one-sided RDMA,
因为它想要做这种单边 RDMA ，
without actually any server involvement.
不需要任何服务器参与。
So using optimistic concurrency control scheme,
所以使用乐观并发控制方案，
that means that, if you want a good performance
这意味着，如果你想要好的性能，
and avoid transaction boards that workload better,
避免事务中止，工作负载更好，
actually, have few conflicts,
很少有冲突，
we're seeing new innovation,
我们看到了新的创新，
there are two common benchmarks that are being used in the transaction literature to measure systems,
有两个基准测试，
for those two benchmarks,
对于这两个基准，
you know clearly as doing extremely well,
做得非常好，
doesn't mean they're not that many conflicts.
意味着它们没有那么多冲突。
The second assumption, it makes is that,
它提出的第二个假设是，
the data must fit in memory,
数据必须存储在内存中，
so it means that if you have a really really big database,
这意味着如果你有一个非常大的数据库，
you have to buy more machines,
你必须买更多的机器，
or if you're really the data too big
或者如果你的数据太大，
and you don't want to buy more machines,
你不想买更多的机器，
then basically you can't use FaRM
那么你不能使用 FaRM ，
and you have to go back to more traditional database,
你必须回到更传统的数据库，
that actually has you know persistent storage
有持久存储，
and so you can read or write record to a much larger storage device.
你可以在更大的存储设备上读取或写入记录。
Replication is only, it's only within the data center.
复制只是在数据中心内进行，
So in that way, in that way, respect,
所以这种方式，
it's quite different from Spanner,
它和 Spanner 有很大不同，
the whole goal, there was to do synchronous transactions across the synchronous replication across data centers,
整个目标必须是，
you know to support applications, that need to be able to survive
为了支持应用程序，
indicates you know FaRM that is just not the case,
FaRM 不是这样的，
it's not targeted to those kinds of applications.
它不是针对那些类型的应用程序的。
And then the final point is,
最后一点是，
it requires you know pretty fancy or exotic hardware,
它需要非常奇特或奇异的硬件，
in particular has two things,
尤其是有两样东西，
this a UPS, [] UPS to survive complete data center outages
UPS ，在数据中心完全故障中存活下来，
and more importantly you know use this RDMA NICs,
更重要的是，使用这种 RDMA 网卡，
you know get actually really high performance.
获得很高的性能。
Okay, that's all I wanted to say about FaRM,
好了，这是关于 FaRM 我想说的，
unless there are any further questions.
除非有任何进一步的问题。
Okay, so that basically ends set of paper or ends transaction side of this 6.824,
好的，这结束了 6.824 的事务的论文，
so we're sort of done three lectures on transactions
所以我们做了三节关于事务的课程，
and that was basically this is the end of talking about transactions,
这是关于事务的讨论的结束，
so will show up in other papers,
也会出现在其他论文上，
but we're not going to talk about any more detail,
但我们不会谈论更多细节，
in fact we're basically sort of done with talking about you know sort of the most challenging part in the distributed systems,
事实上，我们已经完成了
namely building fault tolerant storage systems,
即构建容错存储系统，
and you know we're now seeing a broad spectrum of different designs,
我们看到了各种不同的设计，
including designs that they are actually supports very powerful programming abstraction of transactions.
包括一些设计，
So in the next, this lecture,
所以在接下来的这节课里，
the remaining of this lecture and subsequent lectures,
这节课的剩余部分以及随后的课程，
we're going to sort of look at different topics,
我们将讨论不同的主题，
that were related to storage systems.
与存储系统无关。
And so the first topic, that we're gonna be talking about is spark.
所以我们要讨论的第一个话题是 Spark 。